Caleb M. Vatral

23 East Elm Ave, Quincy, MA 02170

□ (717) 781-0883 | Secaleb.m.vatral@lions.enc.edu | Meww.vatral.net | Deciro kovatral | Deciro caleb.m.vatral | Deciro ca

Professional Summary _

Self-motivated and team oriented individual, who uses a blend of a broad set of academic and technical skills in physics, math, engineering and computer science combined with experience in applied research, software development, and management toward solving real world problems and improving human lives.

Education

Eastern Nazarene College

Quincy, MA

Aug. 2015 - PRESENT

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND MATHEMATICS

GPA: 4.0, Expected Graduation: May 2019

Employment

Advanced Lab Manager

Quincy, MA

DEPARTMENT OF PHYSICS AND ENGINEERING, EASTERN NAZARENE COLLEGE

Aug. 2017 - PRESENT

 Assisted professors in overseeing daily operation in the lab including managing all lab sessions, overseeing all teaching assistants, and facilitating active research projects

Research Assistant Quincy, MA

DEPARTMENT OF PHYSICS AND ENGINEERING, EASTERN NAZARENE COLLEGE

Jun. 2016 - PRESENT

- · Joined with faculty and other students to continue ongoing research in earthquake forecasting full-time during two 10-week summer programs, and part-time during the school year
- Promoted to student manager during summer 2017 research program

Peer Tutor Quincy, MA

CENTER FOR ACADEMIC SUCCESS, EASTERN NAZARENE COLLEGE

Aug. 2016 - PRESENT

- Tutored ENC students in coursework for math and physics classes for a variety of skill levels ranging from elementary level to university sophomore level classes
- Promoted to Senior Tutor in Aug. 2017

Help Desk Assistant

Ouincy, MA

INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY SERVICES, EASTERN NAZARENE COLLEGE

Oct. 2015 - Oct. 2017

 Worked closely with students and staff at Eastern Nazarene College to help solve a variety of personal and departmental technology issues and ensure technology availability and usability for community members

Technical Experience _____

Data Acquisition Platform

A debian-based microcomputer platform with a Python daemon to collect data from remote locations

and transmit to a time-series database on a harded CentOS server for later analysis

Piezo-Magnetic Simulation

A MATLAB simulation of the piezo-magnetic effects due to large magnitude earthquakes as computed

in Sasai (1980)

Magnetic Field Sensor

Designed and tested a low magnitude fluxgate magnetic field sensor for use with measuring

disturbances associated with pre-earthquake signals

Subnet Calculator A HTML and PHP web application to subnet IPv4 networks and get information about specific subnets

Technical Skills ____

Proficient C++, Java, Responsive Web using W3.CSS, Debian and CentOS Linux, Git/Github

Experienced Python, MATLAB, PHP, mySQL, InfluxDB, LaTex

Recent Coursework

C++ Programming 2

Intermediate/Advanced topics in C++ development including object oriented programming and introduction to data

Introduction to Networks Topics in telecommunications including TCP/IP model, OSI model, subnetting, routing, and switching